

ADITI JAIN

Phone: +91-8971848170 | e-mail: adi.lib19@gmail.com | Current Location: Delhi, India

PROFILE SUMMARY

Certified Project Management Professional (PMP) with almost 9 years of experience as a Technical Project Lead for both front-end and full stack applications in Financial Services, E-Commerce, Data Analytics and commodity Trading domain using Agile and Scrum.

TOOLS AND SKILLS

- Web Development Skills Angular 11, PrimeNG, Angular Material, D3.js, Bootstrap, Foundation framework, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, JavaScript, SCSS, Responsive Web Design, w3c accessibility standards
- Tools Gulp, Grunt, Jira, Chrome Dev Tools, Jenkins, Azure DevOps, Gitlab
- Configuration Management: SVN, GIT, IBM Management Center

WORK EXPERIENCE

Team Lead Accenture Aug 2021 – Dec 2021

Team Lead for development and management of internal dashboard for Shell's DSX trading platform. **Platform/Tools:** Angular 11, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Responsive Web Design, Gitlab

- **Technical Program Management** Lead project planning, teamwork review and tasks tracking using GIT. Managed team growth plans for a team of 8 people.
- Trading Platform Development- Developed and directly led 5 engineers in the development and deployment of the key features on the DSX platform using the GitHub workflows.

Technical Lead Evalueserve Sept 2020 – Aug 2021

Technical Lead for end to end delivery for Data Analytics applications focusing on the front end development. **Platform/Tools:** Angular 11, PrimeNG, Angular Material, D3.js, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Responsive Web Design, Azure DevOps

- **Team Leadership** Technical Lead for 5 Engineers for Front-End development and design. Responsible for their career and technical growth.
- **Digital Platform Development** Developed and handled the entire end to end delivery of Data Analytics applications like Market Spend Optimization, Forecasting Tool and Smart Data Management.
- **Data Management** Used Angular with D3.js to help visualize market spend data and other key variables for a dataset of more than 100k on average.
- Cross-company XFN- Drove XFN for UI/UX design, backend and testing teams. Deeply involved in the
 design review and suggestions process for the optimized application view.

Sr. UI Developer

On Demand Agility Software

Jan 2018 – Sept 2020

Development Lead for one of the largest hobby products distributors, Horizon Hobby and Tower Hobbies in the US and Europe market.

Platform/Tools: JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, jQuery, Foundation framework, Responsive Web Design, IBM WCS, IBM Management Center (CMC), GIT, AzureDevOps, ADA, Accessibility, W3C

- **Project Development Lead** Directly lead 2 developers in planning, designing and implementation of the Horizon Hobby's website UI and navigation logic for the EU and the US markets.
- Cross Market Exposure- Developed user-profiles flow, shipping/billing, order confirmation/checkout flow for B2B and B2C.

- **XFN** experience- Responsible for owning and driving XFN partnerships with the design, backend and testing teams.
- **UI Migration Lead** Successfully led the complete migration of Tower Hobbies front-end to Horizon Hobby post acquisition. This included bringing up the entire service with responsive web-design.

Sr. Systems Eng. Infosys Limited Feb 2014 - Jan 2018

Senior Engineer with focus on complete redesign and development of website and internal dashboards for Citizens Bank.

Platform/Tools: Angular 4 and 5, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, jQuery, Jasmine, Karma, Jira, Jenkins, SVN, Foundation framework, Responsive Web Design, ADA, Accessibility, W3C

Citizens Bank Redesign: Worked on the complete redesign of Citizens Bank's 10 years old landing UI.

- **Prototyping and Research** Developed 5+ web prototypes and style guides. Helped in directional inputs for future scalability.
- **Responsive Web Design** Lead a team of 2 engineers to develop banks first working version of a responsive web design that supported multiple device form factors.
- Americans Disability Act Support- Successfully developed a fully ADA compliant website for the bank.
- Cross-company XFN- Lead product discussion and engineering debug sessions for the Bank's key stakeholders.
- **Product Launches & Roll-outs** Launched the updated website to more than 4 million worldwide users.

Citizens Bank Consumer Banking: Developed Front-End features to support banking features for customers.

- Feature design and prototyping- Lead requirement gathering, prioritization and visual design research.
- Responsive Web Design- Directly worked on responsive web design feature implementations that were scalable and cross-device compatible.
- **Product Launches & Roll-outs** Launched & scaled production features regionally by rolling out 10+ high-impact product features.

Assistant Consultant-Development Oodles Technologies May 2013 - Feb 2014

Software engineer for B2B front-end websites development.

Platform/Tools: Groovy and Grails, jQuery, JavaScript, AJAX, Spring Security Tool Suite, GIT, Jenkins

- **Project Development** Developed a website for one of the IT outsourcing marketplace (ITeXchange) with a curated network of over 500 IT service providers using Groovy and Grails.
- Maintenance and Improvements- Responsible for maintenance and front end improvements for Oodles
 Technologies' customer website.

EDUCATION (FULL-TIME) & CERTIFICATION

Year	Program	Major	Institute
10/22 - 10/25	Project Management	People, Process & Business	Project Management
	Professional (PMP)	Domain	Institute
2008 – 2012	B.E.	Computer Science	Inderprastha Engineering
		Engineering	College, India